Kev Kev Tim, good to see you, man. Good
to see you. Let's figure out which one
there we go. Cheers. Cheers. All right.
>> You know, I know the cool kids are down
on alcohol, but every once in a while, I
think there's a place for it.
>> There's a time and place.
>> And this is the time.
>> I think [laughter] this is the time and
the place. And I think paying a tax for
it the next day is a feature, not a bug.
>> Are you getting taxed harder on?
>> Of course. Yeah. Is it getting worse?
>> Every old bastard.
>> Yeah, I know.
>> That's genderneutral. gets taxed as you
can process ethanol less and less well
over time. But I'm cool with it. I don't
have that much, but today has been
hectic.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, take a little hard day. Take a
little edge off.
>> And people may not like the sound of
that. It's a little antiquated maybe for
all the cool ketamine kids. No offense,
[laughter]
>> but don't put that [__] on me. I try it
one time and I get freaking [laughter]
bastard. You [__] a goat once and then
they call me the goat [__] [laughter]
>> Can't get around it.
>> I still stand by that experience
>> when you're doing it in a supervised
setting by a medical professional.
>> Here we go.
>> No, I'm telling you it's You've done it.
>> Of course [snorts] I have.
>> Okay, so there we go.
>> Well, yeah, because I wanted to be able
to speak.
>> I saw you at a party one time and you
were just like,
>> that's not true. [laughter] That's not
true.
>> Still have all my nostrils intact. No
ketamine cramps, you know. I don't even
know what that is. Is that a thing?
>> That's when you use too much.
>> Okay.
>> Way, way, way, way too.
>> Oh, yeah. It hurts bad on the bladder,
right?
>> Yeah. Your bladder can get a little
grumpy or a lot grumpy as the case might
be.
>> Yeah. I'm good.
>> You know, I'm good. Kevin, random show
number 3,479.
>> Yeah. You know what's crazy, dude, is I
looked up a random show the other day
and you had a bit of hair like
[laughter]
way back in the day. way back.
>> We were babies.
>> I know.
>> So much [__] has happened.
>> The only constant I think is like maybe
like Toaster who's barely alive.
[laughter]
>> Toaster. I know. Seriously,
>> Toaster was a tiny tiny little pup.
>> Yeah.
>> Who was chewing through the XLR cables.
>> Oh my god.
>> On your couch in San Francisco way way
way back in the day.
>> Toer's 15.
>> And I'll tell a quick little story. A
week ago, I get this call and Daria
calls me and she's like, "You got to get
over the house. Toaster is shaking
violently and he's 15. He's like running
into walls and [__] you know? He's
getting up there and he's legs are
collapsing so he can't stand up and he
couldn't stand up and he's shaking
violently and I'm like just flying over
there."
>> Mhm.
>> I throw him in my car. He's on my lap
driving, you know, to get to this
emergency vet as fast as possible. And
he just sprays [__] all over me. Like
literally I I heard it like I could felt
his stomach be like
and then like 10 seconds later
>> I'm not even talking like oh like oh he
had a little [__] like no no no no like
shotgun against the car door like the
whole thing. And it's all down my pants.
>> We're toasty.
>> I know. But you know what's funny dude?
It's like I rushed him in and long story
short he's okay now.
>> What was it? He had gone into the vet
the day prior and he was so nervous that
he stood for he had to be there for like
a multi-our blood draw
>> because he was having some other issues
and he stood for like 6 hours straight.
>> That's too long for he can only stand
for like 10 minutes like max.
>> And so he had just overtaxed himself and
got like there's a syndrome that they
can get when they're like super stressed
out and all. So
>> little Molly's had it or big Molly.
She's on the floor right here.
>> She's sleeping. Ollie's 12. It's crazy.
>> But long story short, he's okay. But I
thought to myself, it's so weird because
when I walked in there and there was
like [__] and like I'm literally I'm in
tears cuz I think I'm about to have to
put down my dog, you know?
>> Of course.
>> And I just thought it's okay. I'll do
this any day for this dude. When you
care about your animals that much, none
of that matters.
>> Yeah.
>> Like you would do anything for them. And
it's just like just that love. It's so
crazy how much you love these little
beasts. Like it's insane, dude. It's
like a kid. It's like a kid.
>> Yeah. It's
wild to think about if you really sit
down and think about it. Some of these
super common daily
experiences like communing with a dog or
pointing and having a dog recognize that
you're pointing for instance.
>> That's really rare in the animal
kingdom. That recognition of pointing as
just one example. But how unusual it is
that we have this and yes we have cats.
I grew up with four cats and two dogs. I
get it. But in particular dogs as like
companions,
co-hunters, etc. The fact that we've
evolved co-evolved in a sense
>> and sort of co-domemesticated.
>> Yeah.
>> Also, right, it's not necessarily one
way. Read the botney of desire by
Michael Pollen for more on that
>> is incredible.
>> Yeah. Right. The fact that we have like
we're totally calm having this 60 plus
pound beast with giant fangs on the
floor is nuts.
>> Yeah. I mean, I'm sure you've seen that
those Instagram posts where it's like
where I was and where I am now today and
like they show like the wild like wolf
like out in the countryside like eating
a rabbit and then they show like a
poodle in a tutu outfit and [__] like
all like dme I'm going to go grab some
scraps from those weird monkeys. What's
the worst that could happen? And then
it's like 10,000 years later, right?
with a bonnet on.
>> What else is going on, Kevin? I got a
couple things on my list.
>> There's a lot to talk about.
>> First, I'll say that lately life has
been lifing me. It's been doing all the
things. We lost a dear colleague Malik.
>> Oh man, there started
>> very notorious like just amazing early
tech just creative author
thinker.
>> Very sweet guy.
>> The nicest. Nice.
>> And we lost him within the last week.
>> Yeah, he passed away. So, that was
tough. That was
>> really tough. I found out when I was at
a a retreat. I went to a 5-day silent
meditation retreat, which is great, but
bummer to hear that. But, I mean, this
is the thing that I realized the other
day. I was thinking about, you know,
Toaster and M and other stuff I have
going on and my mom getting older and
following and all these things. And in
some sense, it's unavoidable, number
one, and number two, I kind of wouldn't
have it any other way. It's what makes
life interesting. Like when M passed.
>> You mean death?
>> Well, just everything the chaos of it
all.
>> Yeah.
>> If you can just take a step back and be
like, well, or I could just be sitting
there living a really boring life and
nothing could be happening. Like when
passed, what I felt was a severe sense
of loss and sorrow and sadness. But I
realized that that gap is just love at
the end of the day because I wouldn't
have it unless I loved this man so much.
Like I I cared for this person so much.
How lucky am I to have crossed paths
with this person to get to know them?
>> And you were tied in through True
Ventures obviously and prior to that.
>> Yeah. But like anyone in general that
you lose that you love, you know? I
mean, when I lost my dad, like that is
just a gaping hole of love manifested
through sorrow and sadness.
>> Yeah.
>> And once you realize that, it's like,
wow, I had this great father that did
all these amazing things with me.
>> And you can kind of convert that or just
be okay with it. Not that you need to
change that feeling,
>> right? Recognize that it's a consequence
of the love.
>> It's a consequence of the love, the deep
love.
>> Yeah. You know, I heard about his
passing and I want to give credit where
credit is due for a few things. Matt
Mullenweg,
>> my mutual friend. He was incredibly
close to
>> and I'm really grateful to Matt for a
few things. One, I mean, many things. I
could give a long list, but there are a
few. One is he organized a trip to
Antarctica. I've never been to
Antarctica or hadn't. And on that trip
were just a handful of people including
M. So, I got to spend quality time.
timing. Trust me, when you're [laughter]
in Antarctica, you are indoors most of
the time. What that means is you're
either trying to sleep in your tent, but
it's going to be during the summer, so
it's like a spotlight in your face 24
hours a day,
>> or you're in one of these other
structures where you're probably like
having wine and junk food, let's be
honest. [snorts] And there's a lot of
talking, so we got to hang out. And M
was also an avid photographer. And so,
we got to like go to this nearby empire
penguin colony, which was a once in
a-lifetime experience. and [snorts]
you just sit and talk and
if there were going to be any small
talk, which there wasn't going to be
with M or me really for that matter, it
all falls away after the first half day,
right?
>> And then everybody's kind of like
psychologically naked, right? So, I
really want to thank Matt for that
opportunity to bond with him. And I'd
spent a lot of time with him, but it was
always in these little bits and pieces.
Yeah. You know, not for several days
straight where you're basically like
locked in together.
>> Yeah.
And separately, Matt introduced me to
this short blog post by someone who
typically writes very long blog posts,
Tim Urban, called The Tail End. I don't
know if I ever sent this to you.
>> People should know by way.
>> Yeah, fantastic blog. And the tail end
makes the point among many others that
by the time you I think it's graduate
from high school, let's assume you're
headed off to college away from your
parents, you've spent something like 90
95%
of the total hours you will ever spend
with your parents by the time you
graduate from high school.
>> And when you start to visualize that,
and Tim Urban is really good at laying
it out visually,
>> it can provoke some really profound
changes for me. Yeah. I mean, just
reading that short blog post sent to me
by Matt ended up leading to taking my
family on these family trips as like
awkward and uncomfortable that was at
points cuz my family doesn't really
emote much.
>> Mhm.
>> And so you stick us together in the way
that I was together with and it's it can
be super uncomfortable
>> but making the effort right at least
feeling like look
>> this runway is not infinite.
>> Yeah. And it's like, let me just make
the effort. And I'm glad I did because
we got to a point where it's like with
my dad's mobility, he's really
compromised. He needs a wheelchair now
for a lot.
>> I just saw him a few days ago and it was
great to see him, dude. It was so great
to see him. He's so kind. He's like,
Kevin, like so happy and you know, he
has a little cane and it was just like
so sweet to see him, man. I hadn't seen
him for like years. It had been like
seven years or something like that.
>> Something like that. And I'm glad I took
those trips because before you know it,
you can't do it anymore. And it makes me
think of, you mentioned meditation. This
really good short, I'll call it a
meditation for simplicity, but
>> it's [snorts] like an audiobook chapter
by Sam Harris called The Last Time. I
think it's called The Last Time. And he
reflects on these various experiences
that at the time you don't recognize are
the last time for something, right? So
he he went skiing. He went skiing. He
went skiing. And there was a time when
he stopped, but he didn't realize that
that was going to be the last time,
>> right?
>> And you just [__] don't know. Do you
ever try and like I think about this
dude and then I try and do it one more
time.
>> Yeah, that's right. I always end up
injured, dude. I went to the bouncy
house with my kids and like I'm 49, you
know, and I was like, I'm going to
[__] do a flip right now. And like
literally people were like, "Don't do
it. Don't like like call me off, you Oh,
and I did it and I stuck it and it felt
good.
>> You're good on a trampoline.
>> Might be my last time.
>> It might be your last time. You are good
on a trampoline. This is so weird, man.
Dude, I kid you not. I had a dream last
night of the two of us going to House of
Air at Chrissy Field in San Francisco
and you were doing like front flips off
your knees. You dropped your hat and
then you like kicked the trampoline to
bounce it back up to your head and I was
like, "What?"
>> Wait, wait, wait, wait. So, you know, I
sent you that video of me dropping my
hat and kicking it back.
>> You can do it live, too. Yeah. Yeah.
Okay. So, it was just made it way in the
dream
>> and I was just like, "What?" I literally
had that in my dreams last night. That's
wild.
>> And I had the assless chaps on like I
normally do when you're
>> Yeah, you had the ass traps on which
like depending on your angle can be kind
of awkward.
>> Yeah, exactly. Cuz you like doing the
straddle flip. [laughter]
>> So, it's a little awkward.
>> I've heard about these dreams before.
[laughter] I know.
>> I always text them to Kevin. I'm like, I
was thinking of you last night.
>> The chaps were back. [laughter]
>> So, what do you got, man? I mean, people
should check out My hands are too
sweaty, so I'm thinking about
>> death.
>> Yeah. In the chat. [laughter]
>> Wow, that's the perfect audio.
>> The uh Well, the retreat was fantastic.
I spent 5 days going really deep on my
[__] doing a lot of work on it.
>> Moo,
>> which you can listen to Henry Shikman on
your podcast if people are interested
about what Zen is all about, like real
true traditional Zen with coons. And you
probably heard that sound of one hand
clapping. That actually is a one of 500
plus cohons. Yeah, it was fantastic. I
had a couple little micro insights,
which was good. And I was
[clears throat] kind of rushed through
to the Zen master to explain them and
try and get some clarity on them, which
is great.
>> How do you know that you're having a
micro insight? So, it's not like my
balls are shaving in this position. It's
something else.
>> Yes. [laughter] This
but close. No, I essentially was sitting
and you know Henry, one of the Zen
masters who you've had on the show, uh
dear friend of ours was there and then
his Roshi from Japan was there. So it's
very special and then comes every two
years.
>> What's his name? Yamada
Roshi. Yeah. So basically I was kind of
pulled Henry aside. You're not supposed
to. He's not talking. But I was like
he's like you know how's it going? Like
this and that. And I was like well I had
this thing happen. What do you think
about this? And he's like, "You got to
come with me right now."
>> Well, not come with me, but he like got
me right in front cuz there's a line to
see the Roshi to go have your private
interview where you go and like check
your practice with them. Yeah.
>> So, it's behind closed doors. You go in,
you sit down with the Roshi. You
typically get between two and 10 minutes
to sit down and talk about your progress
on your practice. And you do that like,
you know, once every day and a half when
you're out there.
>> Mhm.
>> That's cool.
>> Enough to where Henry was like, "You
should go talk to him right away.
>> Skip the line." TSA preaching. go
through the free check and it was
beautiful and it was a it was a micro
little thing.
>> I can share it if you're curious.
>> Yeah, of course I'm curious.
>> Yeah. So, I'm looking forward to hearing
myself talk. That's why I'm here talk to
you.
>> So, I'm sitting here staring against the
wall because in Zen you stare against
the wall with your eyes open and you're
staring about 3/4 down kind of just
glancing out. I'm working on my co and
for people that don't know how you do
that is essentially on the outreath you
just slowly internally
say your co. It's almost like a mantra
in some sense, but a little bit more
involved. [clears throat and snorts]
>> Yeah. It's like a question you're kind
of asking yourself slowly that doesn't
make sense and eventually it pops. But
what happened is I had about two seconds
of this sense that
there was and this is going to be hard
to explain because it's not from the
world of thought which is already hard
to explain.
>> It's like a sneeze in the perennium. No.
>> No.
>> All right.
>> Close. I had a sense of nothing lacking.
>> That sounds nice.
>> Nothing needed to be added and nothing
even possibly could be added and nothing
possibly could be taken away because
everything
at that moment was full in the way that
it should be.
>> But what was interesting about it is
it wasn't an emotion. It was just like a
steady state of being. So it wasn't
like, "Oh, I feel free right now." No,
none of that. It was just like, "Oh,
this everything is here
perfectly present."
And it was just
wild. Wild in what sense? In the felt
sense of that experience or
>> wild in the sense that wild in the I
just drank too much tequila after not
having much tequila since. I haven't had
any tequila, but in the sense that we
often times so often like go inside in
in our into our brain to try and find
something, figure something out, an
emotional state that's either bothering
you or feels good or feels bad or
something else. And then just to know
that everything, and I don't mean like
objects, everything was one
unit of nothing lacking.
>> Mhm. And it was just a micro sense of
kind of like, oh, there's actually
nothing to do because everything's
already here.
>> Yeah.
>> And they talk about this in Zen a bit
where you already have everything that
you need. [laughter]
>> So it's just they call the removal of
the veil. Mhm.
>> So it's like it's an expansive awareness
that you get from
a deep continued practice over years and
decades.
>> Mhm.
>> But it was already there all along.
>> Can I give a shameless plug?
>> Yeah, let's hear it.
>> All right. So you and I are both
involved with the way which is this
guided single path meditation app which
is guided by Henry Shukman who you
mentioned
>> and it's the
sort of progressive development of
skills on a single path which I really
like as opposed to just what is the
meditation dour with no coherence
>> and a few of my favorite meditations I
have a lot of different sessions
bookmarked and I've done hundreds and
hundreds and hundreds. And by the way,
for people who are like, "Ah, these guys
are just shilling their bags."
>> I do think it can be a good business,
but this is sort of a ideologically
philosophical
investment
>> of time and money, right?
>> It's like the reason we invested in the
dog aging study with rapomy. Like
University of Washington, it's like this
needs to exist.
>> These exist,
>> it's good for the world. Let's try it.
Yeah. So, sure, we've got some chips on
the table, but this is this is mostly
because we believe in it.
>> And a few of my favorites, if people
ever try it,
Whole Earth is Medicine is one. Another
one is This Too is me, which makes me
think about what you're saying.
>> So, this too is me
>> is a meditation led by Henry, which this
is going to sound maybe esoteric, but
it's not. When you recognize that
all of the things you experience are
mediated by your mind,
>> right? And therefore, like when you hear
something, when you feel something, when
you're interrupted by something,
etc., etc., anything you can possibly
imagine experiencing is also you because
ultimately
it is entirely mediated by your mind.
Let's just use that instead of brain.
[snorts] And it's incredibly, at least
for me, and I'm not comparing it to your
experience because I think it's probably
characteristically different, is
incredibly relaxing to let go even just
for a moment because my brain is like
the ultimate
[laughter]
like
>> dog chasing a squirrel kind of brain,
right? Like I'm always looking for
something to fix, something to improve,
what I need to do, what is happening
next week. And meditation is
>> you are the squirrel.
>> I am the squirrel. It [laughter] right.
It can be excruciatingly painful, right?
Like meditation can be super hard.
>> That's a very common thing. People are
like, I can't do this.
>> But when Henry gives you permission to
include all of that as you I know this
might sound very bizarre. It allows you
to kind of drop this burden that you
didn't realize you were carrying. So, in
any case, you don't have to do a
week-long meditation retreat if you're
just doing 10 minutes twice a day. And I
do think there's some alchemy to twice a
day. I don't know why exactly. I have
some theories around Vegas nerve
stimulation and stuff, but you get a lot
out of it.
>> So, in any case, I didn't mean to
interrupt your story. No, I think
there's two things that I love that
Henry says quite often when he starts
some of these meditations, which is take
everything that you came in the door
with, like all the thoughts, worries,
emotions, things, and leave it at the
door just for now.
>> You can come back to it in 20 minutes,
>> but just for now. The permission to set
those things down for yourself just for
now
>> is such a beautiful thing. And then like
the little instructions where he's like,
"Drop your jaw an eighth of an inch."
Yeah.
>> And I'm like, "Whoa, I didn't even
realize I was Can I tell you something
crazy about that?"
>> Yeah.
>> All right. So, I got fitted for a
mandibular device, which is a fancy way
of saying a double-decker mouthpiece.
>> Yeah.
>> That is an easier approach to resolving
sleep apnnea or snoring. So, I don't
snore a ton, but every once in a while I
do. Drives my lady insane,
understandably. And if you take the jaw
and drop it down an eighth of an inch
and forward an eighth of an inch, you
open your airway.
>> Mhm.
>> And I was thinking about that because
Henry will often say, as you're alluding
to, like drop your jaw
>> and leave it forward as if it's resting
on a small pillow ever so slightly, and
it increases your air flow.
>> Mhm. I mean, these ancients hit on some
stuff by trial and error
>> that really just works. It's like, yeah,
if you want to have better respiration
while you're meditating
>> and better alignment and blah blah blah
blah blah,
just do what Henry's describing. And I
will say his doulet British tones.
>> Yeah.
>> If you just want a relaxing voice,
>> Yeah. that will help you with chilling
the [__] out when your monkey mind is
ricocheting inside your skull. Like, try
Henry out. Like, you can find free stuff
everywhere. I've had him on the podcast
a bunch as well as meditation Mondays
for a while, which were these very short
episodes of guided meditations. In any
case,
>> yeah, it's great.
>> I've been so It's the right word. I mean
overjoyed is this sounds too dramatic
but I'll just say happy for you to watch
your path with meditation cuz it seems
like you get so much nourishment and
grounding from it and no offense like
you're kind of a spaz you're kind of
[laughter]
>> you're kind of spazz like you get
excited about [__] and then you drop
stuff that is very well exemplified and
like Tim you got to buy this stock and
then you never tell me when you sell and
I'm like oh [__] I'm [__] Oh, but you
want to talk about hold [laughter] cuz
you winner.
>> Yeah,
>> you should have held. It's fine.
>> No, but anyway, literally Tim gives me
this tip and I'm like, "All right, I'm
in." And then like a day and a half
later, I'm down like I know that's why
you got to wait. But the point of the
story is I thought this meditation thing
just like every nine months you're like
I'm moving to Android. I'm like, "Let me
start the timer for two weeks before you
come back to iPhone. [laughter]
I'm like, "Yeah, this meditation thing."
Yeah, sure. We'll see. I give it two
weeks. And you've stuck with it.
>> Come up on five years now.
>> Yeah. It's really made me
happy as your friend to see something
that gives you that consistency.
>> That's it. There's nothing more to add.
I've been really, what's the right word?
Not sure of the right way to put it.
I've just been very reassured.
>> Yeah. by you having that constant in
your life.
>> One of the things I'm curious about,
speaking of constants and kind of like
how things changed since we've known
each other and you had hair and all that
other [__] My hair wasn't great.
>> Still got plenty of hair. It's not on my
head. Yeah, [laughter]
>> exactly. The braids down there. Um the
the question I'm I'm I'm curious about
is I've been thinking a lot lately as I
kind of march towards 50. What are the
things that I've always said that I want
to do that I'm just like, you know, I've
got a thousand bookmarks on Instagram
like all these Japanese woodworking
things and like
>> it's always woodworking little always
woodworking.
>> Well, I even have, you know, this is how
bad of my speaking the monkey mind and
bouncing around. I literally have for
some reason the algorithm is now giving
me like those [__] boats inside
of bottles. People making the boats in
the bottles and I'm like am I going to
be a boat in the bottle guy? Like I
don't know. Maybe. Like I realize now I
think these next couple decades
>> I want to stop bullshitting myself and
stop saying like hey one day
>> one day I'll get in Japanese
woodworking. One day I'll do this and
really start doing some things.
>> Yeah.
>> You've been really good cuz you archery
hunting like the stuff that you've
gotten into you've gone deep on in the
last few years.
>> Yeah. Super deep. Are there any things
that are on your kind of bucket list of
things where you say one day, you know,
you're busy with your podcast and all
the [__] you got going podcast, shoot me
in the head. It's [laughter] it's fine
and it's fun most of the time, but it's
so crowded and it's like, man, if if 20
other people are trying to do the same
job, I don't want to do this job.
>> Yeah. Right.
>> It is wild how many new podcasters there
are out there that they're also
optimizing every little freaking thing.
all the thumbnails like what you need to
know before your crypto crashes next
week now and I'm like ah god
>> I just don't want to play that game. And
>> for me I would say the most top of mind
is rock climbing. Actually I just did
some outdoor rock climbing a couple days
ago and
>> I love rock climbing. I was always for
at least the last 15 years limited by my
right elbow which I had surgically
repaired. So, it's ready to go. And I
want to do some multi- pitch stuff in
Yose,
>> dude. Let's go.
>> Yeah. So, I don't know if I want to say
this. [laughter]
>> All right, that's a good start. So, you
is a big rock climber.
>> Yeah. And he goes, he goes out to
Euseite.
>> I'm sure
>> we should go cuz he's invited me to go
up there and do some climbing.
>> He looks like someone who would be good.
>> Apparently, he's amazing. So, and I'm
like, dude, I can't go do multi- pitch
with you. And he's like, ah, just come
out. We'll have fun. Blah blah blah.
>> No, that's how you end up [__]
[laughter]
>> Exactly.
>> I did multi- pitch when I was like 24
and it was like three pitches.
>> Like I didn't I [laughter] didn't do
ease.
>> Yeah. No, that's a commitment.
>> Yeah. So the idea of having something
like that to strive for having some type
of physical goal like that for me is
very helpful because just
not dying like training to not die
sooner than is necessary is not
sufficient for me. I'm just like that's
such a
>> depressing uninvigorating goal.
>> I'd much rather have something
>> that has a deadline, right? It's like,
"All right, you need to be able to do
X." In the case of the archery, it's
like Lancaster Classic. Here's the date.
You need to do this type of training and
this type of volume with this type of
deliberate practice.
>> Yeah.
>> In order to be prepared to train and
then compete, right? Okay.
>> Similarly, for something like a multi-
pitch, it's like, okay, you can break
that down. And I just enjoy doing that
stuff,
>> dude. So, let me ask you a question. The
number two, I don't know if you saw this
on my my story list. The number two
story I had was this guy Michael
Eckhart. Do you know who? No. No idea.
>> Oh my god. Okay. So, Herman and Rogan,
all these guys, they've talked about him
publicly about this guy. He has won
multiple pull-up world championships.
>> Okay.
>> And dude, when you watch him do a
pull-up, he's kind of one of those guys
that can bring the bar all the way down
and do like the circer and all that
stuff.
>> Yeah. Like where you can walk with your
feet and [__] all the calisthenic
stuff. But he has a series of videos
that that teach you how to do finger
strength training
>> and I bought his course and I'm doing
this right now. But you got me into that
wooden device.
>> The nug.
>> The nug. So dude, you got to watch his
videos. They're amazing. Like seriously,
Joe's really into him. Like this guy
name is Michael Eckhart. You can find
him on Instagram. And it's all about
grip strength, pull-ups, and he's not
big, but he's shredded. Yeah. And I
think when I think about like the next
10 years, like I don't need to be big
big. It's probably not what you want,
>> right? Especially for rock climbing.
>> Yeah. Exactly. I mean, you need to be
lean, right? And strong. And that's what
I love about this. So, I'm getting into
I'm doing these every single day. Well,
I'm 2 days in, but [laughter]
I'm getting into it, you know. But tell
us about the nug, cuz that was something
that you turned me on to.
>> The nug. I mean, I have it in my
suitcase at the hotel here.
It's just a simple little
wooden device. It looks like a very
large bar of soap with these different
indentations carved into the sides and
>> like little finger indentations.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, you can use a
carabiner to connect it to say a cable
machine of some type in any gym. And
look, you could use a loading pin and
all this then the other thing and a
daisy chain. But let's put that aside.
at a gym, you could use a cable and
connect it through the loop with a
carabiner and work on your hand
strength.
>> And you brought this to Santa Fe when we
were out there doing that meditation
thing.
>> I did. Yeah. I mean, it's literally
something small enough to slip into my
sweatshirt pocket. So, it's easy to
travel with.
>> I always travel with that and a band for
multiple purposes for like something
called DNS kind of core exercises. And I
>> Oh, yeah. I know DNS.
>> Yeah. So, I use a band for that and it's
incredibly easy to travel with
>> and then a handful of other things.
Something called an alpha ball, which I
use for different types of kind of
mobility. It's the size of like a very
large soft ball. And all this stuff fits
into the corner of a suitcase. And then
I'll do also something that maybe we
haven't talked about called Abrahes,
which so Abraham Hamson, Emil
Abrahamson, very well-known rock climber
on YouTube. And Abra hangs
>> I'm writing this down right now. Abra
hangs.
>> Abra hangs are pretty simple. I mean,
it's partial body weight hangs in
different positions for 10 seconds on,
50 seconds off for 10 minutes. And you
do that twice a day. And it's very very
moderate in intensity
>> with like a wooden kind of rock climbing
kind of like
>> use a hangboard. Yeah.
>> I mean you could also use a pull-up bar
depending on how you position your
hands.
>> And that's what I was doing in Santa Fe
was that kind of stuff. 10 seconds on 50
seconds off. And
>> the endurance and strength gains that
you get in your hands are just insane.
Your I should say your lower arms.
>> And
it really helps. So, I've been doing
indoor climbing, but ultimately I'm
like, you know what? As a stretch goal,
multi- pitch outdoor yuseite.
>> Yeah.
>> And I am deadly terrified of heights.
Deadly. Like just talking like look,
look at my hands. Like I'm sweaty just
talking about.
>> Dude, when I watch Free Solo, my hands
are sweating the entire time.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> For people that haven't seen that
documentary, even if you're not into
rock climbing, that is amazing.
>> Yeah. Watch Free Solo. It'll freak you
out. So, that's one that I'm thinking
about going deep on. I'd say that's very
high up on the list because
>> that's awesome, dude. We're going to be
Let's do that together. I'm totally
down. I'm into it.
>> I am totally into it. I mean, rock
climbing when approached in a reasonable
way, like a systematic, reasonable way,
not with like crazy dino movements on
bouldering necessarily. I mean, look,
younger bodies can handle it. Certain
bodies can handle it. My body, not so
much.
>> Yeah.
>> I do not want to fall repeatedly from
10, 15 feet up. I'm just not into it.
So,
In the case of doing it reasonably
though, for instance, I spent a bunch of
time I've spent a lot of time in Utah
and climbing in some of the Salt Lake
City indoor gyms. You have incredible
athletes and I'll I'll make that a
little finer tuned. When I would go to
the gym, it was generally like 11:00
a.m., right? Who the hell goes to the
rock climbing gym at 11:00 a.m. on a
weekday? These are retirees
>> and moms. So you would see for instance
these like 60, 70, 75, almost 80 year
olds were doing like 5'11 plus.
>> This is when you were single. So that
was like prime hunting. [laughter]
>> Exactly. Cougarville. And
you would just see these people in their
60s and 70s doing things that I could
not even imagine doing with complete
inversion on overhangs.
>> Oh yeah. I've seen this. 60, 70 ft up,
you had the national speed climbing
team, you had Olympians, but more than
like the young guns, right, the
15year-olds who are doing all this crazy
stuff because they're impervious.
>> Yeah.
>> It was the people in their 60s and 70s
who were climbing every day that
inspired me to want to take this more
seriously. So, I was like, "Okay,
>> I want to play the long game here.
>> What can I do that's fun? It's a puzzle.
There's a lot of Tetris.
>> They literally call bouldering they call
them problems.
>> Yeah. Problems. Yeah. Exactly. And so
there's a lot of brain power involved
and also it's just to give an idea of
the technicality. I mean there are for
example women who cannot do five
pull-ups who can climb 513 514. That's
very very very very hard. Just for
people who have no reference point like
world class like 514 515 like insane
insane. Like that's when you're in the
magazines.
>> And it's because of sort of the
technical adeptness. And yeah, there's
like ape index and other physiological
factors that play into it. But that is a
very long answer to your question of
what I'm thinking about now, which is
rock climbing. The archery was great and
the competition was fantastic. I love
competing. However, archery is by
definition incredibly solitary. like
you're just by yourself doing the same
thing over and over and over again
thousands of times.
>> And
I have had enough of that in my life.
I've hit my quota.
>> I want to hang out with other people.
>> Timing is super social cuz you'll sit
there and if neither of you can do it,
you'll you'll be like, "Ah, like what if
you put your like foot in like that and
like kind of lunged up that way and
stretched, you know what I mean? Like
>> Yeah. And then you can ask other people
for tips like beta, right? Hey, can you
give me some beta on this?"
>> It's fun.
>> It's really fun. I just love it. You
know, I wanted to mention something if
people haven't read it. The Blade
Itself, which is a series, it's not very
long. I think it's two or three volumes
by Joe Abberrombie. It's fantasy novels.
They're really good. The audio books are
incredible. And the reason I thought of
this, the Blade itself,
is because of our conversation around M
and Toaster. And you know, a friend of
mine just died in a plane crashes. Less
than two weeks.
>> Wait, the one that the Nets one that
went you knew him?
>> Yeah, Josh.
>> Oh, god. That was a latitude, too.
>> Yeah, I know. I know. I know. So, you
just don't know when your time is up.
And in the blade itself, I mean, there
are a lot of [snorts] serious sucks.
>> Yeah. Thanks. And we weren't like super
close friends, but certainly like
friendly, you know, acquaintances like
we've It wouldn't be strange to text.
>> And you just don't know when your time
is up. And the blade itself explores
this in a million different dimensions.
It's really really outstanding. I've
read I say that as someone who's read a
lot of fantasy
and it just talks about the randomness
of life or death and war, right? It's
like you happen to like squat down, take
a [__] and the guy next to you gets an
arrow through the head. It's like it's
just dumb luck.
>> Yeah. Yeah. which is a way to I suppose
reiterate the gratitude piece that you
were mentioning earlier. So, I mean
that's going to be a tough act to
follow, but [laughter]
where do you want to go from that?
>> Yeah, I mean a few things. Let's change
it up into Well, let's just go straight
into like working out. Have you tried
this?
>> Yeah, I have actually.
>> Okay. I really like it. So for people
that are on audio, I just got turned on
to this new protein called Pioneer
Pastures and it's 30 grams in this
little tiny shake.
>> It's A2, so it has lactose removed and
it's also from that special genetic cow.
Do you know more about the A2? Can you
speak to
>> I've heard about the A2. I don't know a
whole lot about it. It's like the whole
and some other cow and da da da da.
>> More people tolerate A2 better than not.
I don't get any stomach issues or
anything with this type of whey protein.
Anyway, I'm not an investor or any [__]
like that. You can get it at Target or
whatever. It's tasty as hell and it's 30
grams and I don't know like I'm trying
if you're trying to put a little muscle
mass on.
>> I love that this is next to the Lo
tequila.
>> Yeah, exactly. I mean, you can mix them
if you want.
>> Everything a growing boy needs.
>> Anyway, I just I just wanted to know if
you had tried it cuz like we always This
is the random show. We talk about [__]
>> Yeah, I tried it.
>> You like it?
>> I do. Yeah. There was a gym I can't
remember exactly. I think it Brooklyn
Barbell Club where they sold this and I
tried it then and I did. Yeah. Tolerated
it super well. didn't get the grumpy
guts. Yeah.
>> As one might.
>> What's your favorite protein? Out of
curiosity.
>> I mean, my protein, I mean, this is a
softball pitch, but
>> funny you should ask, Kevin,
>> and look, I'm involved with this one,
but you know what? I It's like I always
disclose. Have you noticed how few
[__] people disclose what they're
involved with? They're like, "Yeah, I've
heard of this great thing. Oh my god."
And they never disclose they're
involved. The fact that
>> you could literally go to jail for that
[__]
>> No, I know. Uh, but the FTC doesn't
enforce that stuff. Anyway, I mean,
right now, like I'm traveling with Maui
Nui as usual. This one though is kind of
interesting.
>> I probably get 40% of my protein from
Maui Newi venison. This is wild
harvested axis deer from Hawaii. There's
a long story there, but incredibly
nutrientdense.
>> I love this [__] And this is not an ad,
but I do have a hard question for you.
Like a real hard question. And this is
how you know that it's not an ad because
what I'm about to say. Let's hear it.
>> Processed meat nitrates
>> linked to a lot of cancer and bad [__]
>> What are your thoughts on that?
>> This is very very very minimally
processed. So you can get summer sausage
or the sticks. This is free of most of
that [__]
>> What do you think that is? Cuz it is
real. Like people that eat more like
nitrate processed ultrarocessed meats.
>> Yeah. If it's ultrarocessed and the
shelf life is like 3 years, I would
raise an eyebrow and probably hit pause.
So the fact of the matter is most of
this stuff that is minimally processed
almost definitionally is not going to
last very long on the shelf.
>> What do they mean by minimally processed
when you see like a a meat stick? Like
what do you think about like that versus
is it the amount of salt content that
creates the nitrates? No, no, it's
actually nitrates are a totally separate
category. So you're looking to I think
an easy heruristic for this is just
shelf life, right? Like how long will
this
>> How long are those?
>> Uh your eyes are going to be better than
mine. If you can read the size two font
on this, then you can tell me.
>> Good then.
>> Give it a go. I'll buy you some time. In
the meantime,
>> 27 years.
>> No, I'm just kidding. Yeah. [laughter]
>> 25 years.
>> It doesn't say on here.
>> Yeah, it'll say somewhere on the box.
There we go.
>> Oh, buy.
>> Yeah, 27. So, it's like less than one
year, I think, actually. Looking at
here.
>> Yeah, less than one year. Wow. And what
makes this interesting is that this I
give also Molly looks really good for 12
years.
>> Mhm.
>> I give her probably two or three of
these a week. The way I think of this,
this is peppered 10. So they're a bunch
of these different sticks. Like every
professional team you can imagine uses
these things in their training. But this
is made with wild harvested venison,
liver, and heart. So it has some organ
meat in it. You do not taste that. It
just tastes like regular jerky stick.
But I treat this like a multivitamin. So
it's like I take, let's call it two or
three of these a week and limit it to
that and then the rest of the time I'm
taking their other either peppered or
regular sticks. But this is when I'm on
the go. I mean literally this was in my
bag when I got here, right?
>> When I'm on the go, I'm traveling with
this. Probably some nuts of some type
like pistachios or whatever. Walnuts
pretty good for a host of reasons. And
that's about it. I mean, I might have a
couple of servings of exogenous ketones,
but I haven't taken that stuff in a
couple of months.
>> You told me. You freaked me out. It
messes up your liver. This is a
controversial topic. So, yeah, there are
certain [laughter]
exogenous ketones that contain something
called 13b butane dial. It's very
common, and there's a lot of debate
around this. So, the jury is still out,
but some people believe that that can
produce liver toxicity.
So, I consume anything with 13 butane
dial in moderation.
>> Now, to play devil's advocate to a
counterpoint, a lot of the people who
are putting forth that hypothesis or
claiming that's true are selling their
own ketone salts. So, they're actually
selling a competitive product. I see. I
see.
>> So, question mark.
But I mean look, you can look at the
peer-reviewed literature and decide for
yourself. What I have decided personally
is that you should use the exogenous
ketones very intermittently. I have
experimented a lot with every type of
exogenous ketone you can imagine. I
mean, you got me on that good [__] It's
expensive as hell, but like that stuff
goes straight to your head. The one that
you didn't want. We can talk about it.
>> You know what's funny is like when Tim
This is how you know it's good off
camera. Tim's like, "I don't want to
mention the brand because if I do, it'll
sell out and I won't be able to get my
own supply." And that's how I knew I was
like, "That's some good shit." And Tim
wants to guard his own supply of it.
Like, you know, it's good. Yeah. And it
is good, but it's BHB.
I won't get too much into the
technicality here, but it's beta
hydroxybutyrate bonded to 13 butin dial.
So, you're still getting that 13b butane
dial, which means you should take it in
moderation, but
in a pinch when you want it for a
podcast or something like that, man, it
really works.
>> It does work.
>> It really works. And I mean, I've given
it to relatives with dementia
>> and within 20 minutes their sentences
have like 5xed in length and they're
more acute verbally. It's wild. How do
you give it? I wish they had it in pill
form because in some sense it's really
hard to give that to someone that has
dementia because it's like it tastes
like gasoline. It doesn't taste great.
It's not the worst thing. I mean, I've
had a lot of foul stuff in my life. I
just did a shot with this person and I
was like, I'll do it with you and then
we went for a walk and that was it.
There are some concerns around 13 butane
dial and balance. So, particularly in
older adults, you do not want to
contribute to any risk of breaking a
hip.
>> Yeah, 100%.
>> That's just the death nail for a lot of
people.
>> I just had to put my mom into a
different home. It's actually kind of
cool. It's sad, but she's been falling
and they had this like like new AI orb
that sits up there and it kind of does
like a kind of radar type situation
>> and it detects falls.
>> Oh, wow. So the second she falls in the
home like they can rush in and like help
her out and all that and they they
carpet the hell out of it now and stuff
like that. So
>> how do you think about sort of preg
grieving that or contending with that
yourself
>> in terms of
>> with family? That's rough. I mean
>> yeah I mean
>> doesn't sound easy cuz if you like play
forward the tape right it's like I mean
I think about this with my own parents
and it's just like nobody nobody lasts
forever. It's one of those things where
it's so funny because when you're a
teenager and I remember when my dad was
having a hard time standing and this was
like when I was much younger before he
passed and I was like, "Oh, dad's going
to be in like the thing that I might
have to like push him on it if he has to
sit down." Kind of those walkers that
can also be something you can push
somebody on.
>> I was so embarrassed, you know? I was
like, "Oh, people are looking at us or
whatever."
>> And now I like push my mom with pride in
her walker thing. And I'm like,
>> I don't know. You don't know when it's
going to what's going to happen, but the
only thing you can do is just make sure
to show up, you know, and hang out.
>> And and I'm very lucky that my mom has
dementia, but it's it is a type that
>> it's not Alzheimer's, so it's probably
vascular or something.
>> So, I can walk in and she knows who I
am. She can't tell what she had for
breakfast, but she knows who I am, which
is like, I'll take that all day long for
sure, you know? So,
>> yeah.
>> I know you have family members that are
in the same boat, which is tough. a ton
of family members with Alzheimer's. I
mean, literally, I got a call from one
of my relatives wanting to discuss
interventions and it's a tough
conversation because there really isn't
much like you have to, as far as I can
tell, act preemptively, which is why
actually this relates to another bullet
of mine.
>> Do you have five?
>> What was that?
>> How many bullets did you have?
>> Oh, [laughter] how many bullets? Yeah,
that was good. of all of all the rye
whisies. It's the only one that I can
tolerate. I loathe stationary bikes. I
just I I really find stationary biking
to be one of the most soul crushing
things in the world.
>> It's the worst.
>> However, yeah, I mean, I've tried
Pelaton and didn't like the ergonomics
and so on for a bunch of reasons. And
then I have tried very expensive, very,
very expensive setups recommended to me
by fancy doctors. and so on which are
just like too uncomfortable. Like I'm
incredibly hunched over like my back is
basically parallel with the floor.
>> What are you talking about?
>> And I'm like kneing myself in the
stomach. It's so
>> uncom. What are you talking?
>> No. No. I'm talking about getting on
like a stationary bike. But if you're in
like a racing position,
>> you have to adopt this hunchback. And
like there are a million reasons why I
find that uncomfortable.
>> There is a bike, however, it's very easy
to find. It's pretty common in public
gyms called the Kaiser M3i
studio indoor bike. I don't know why
they have to make it so difficult in its
nomenclature, but the Kaiser M3i is
unique in my experience in that you can
elevate the handlebars enough to sit in
a comfortable position with a decent
saddle, meaning the seat such that I can
do the V2 and the V4 and all of that
training
>> for me in a comfortable position without
compromising my low back, which has been
a huge step forward. So, this is the
only bike that I've used consistently
>> for this kind of training. And I was
having a number of conversations with a
neuroscientist named Dr. Tommy Wood over
a period of weeks. And if for instance
you do something called the Norwegian
4x4, there's data to suggest that if you
do it's V2 max training, so it's very
very very intense, but it's like
>> 4 minutes on 3 to four minutes off.
Let's just call it 3 minutes. Four
minutes on, three minutes off and you do
that for four rounds. This is the only
bike that I've been able to use to do
this consistently. And if you do that
for I think it's three times a week
>> for five to six months, the
volutric changes, meaning the
neuroanatomical changes in the
hippocampus and other areas that are
certainly indicated in things like
Alzheimer's lasts for up to 5 years.
>> Wow. So if you do 5 to 6 months of
gutting it out three times a week, the
result [__] the dividends pay off for it
seems up to or possibly beyond 5 years.
>> Holy [__]
>> Crazy. So
>> throwing some sauna in there and you're
like
>> well that's why I'm doing Yeah. I'm
doing all the usual stuff, right? I'm
doing the sauna and
>> don't let perfect be the enemy of good.
You know what I mean? It's like okay,
sure. You don't have 30 minutes to do
like do 10 minutes. Like you can't do a
sauna, take a hot bath. Like,
>> yeah,
>> figure it out.
>> You know what my good is that I like?
>> What's that?
>> It's not perfect, but it's good. Which
is I go on my treadmill. I set it to
4.75
or something incline.
>> So, it's like not crazy, but it's not,
you know, I can still do [__]
>> Yeah.
>> And I set it to only like 2.5 on the
walking.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'll play Duolingo chess cuz they
have chess on there now for Duolingo.
They teach you chess. It's amazing. And
you can play friends and live people and
all that stuff and they do game replays
and like teach and I'm learning a ton.
>> Yeah.
>> And 30 40 minutes go by and you're
drenched in sweat. I know it's not high
intensity and all the benefits on the
the cognitive side seem to be around
like a lot of highend hits.
>> Yeah. But who knows?
>> But it's good.
>> It's doing something right. So I've
really enjoyed that. Like if you if you
just want something
>> to both be like learning and engaged and
kind of like having fun.
>> Yeah. So, you forget about the time. Do
you know what I'm talking about? Where
it's like you just like, "Oh, wait. What
time is it? Oh, [__] I've been on for
37 minutes. I can get off now." You
know? Like I I love that type of cardio.
>> Yeah. I mean, for me, I mean, this is
this is going to sound like maybe a step
down, but it's like the older I get, the
more I realize a little goes a long way.
Like yesterday for instance, I had a
bunch of stuff stacked up and I won't
bore people with the commitments, but I
didn't really have any time to go to the
gym and it was my day to go to the gym
to do X, Y, and Z exercise. And I went
in and I did three sets. I was literally
in there for 5 minutes and I left.
>> But it's better than nothing,
>> right? Totally
>> right. Something is better than nothing.
I'm not going to go to the Olympics with
that approach, but let's [__] be
real. I'm not going to
>> You're never going to lose it.
[laughter]
>> I mean, maybe as like a bystander like
like in the [laughter]
>> Oh, man. So, I'll throw some new random
stuff in there. There's a study that got
my attention. It's been It's been out
since 2025.
September 202. This is in Jamma.
And this is the title. single treatment
with MM120 and then in parenthesis
laseride I think is how that's
pronounced in generalized anxiety
disorder
>> GAD GAD. [laughter]
This is a randomized clinical trial
looking at anxiety which is often
comorbid meaning happening at the same
time as depressive disorders and I think
this is sponsored by a company called
Definium which used to be MindMed.
>> I know where this is going. I just
looked it up. Oh my god.
>> Yeah. Well, what's interesting about
this, and they're not going to maybe
love my comparison, but so MM120 Leride,
I mean, it's comparable to LSD,
>> right?
>> And this is a multi-arm clinical trial.
They did five arms, which is rare to do
because the risk is that they'll blend
together. So the arm means a group who
has is treated with a different
intervention in this case. So they've
got placebo, 25 micrograms, 50
micrograms, 100 micrograms, and 200
micrograms. 100 mics.
>> That's what they give standard for LSD.
>> That's that's what you can think of as a
standard hit. 100 micrograms.
>> And the results are wild, man. If you
look at the ham a score, this is up to
12 weeks out. You can see, I'll just
show you how [clears throat] it's dose
dependent. the more you take basically
the better it goes up to and I'm not
sure how long the follow-ups continued
but where you land is you see that like
the 100 micrograms and 200 are very very
close to it like 25 and 50 are certainly
a lot higher
>> now are you still getting the same
psychedelic experience
>> with this stuff or
>> in the case of this particular compound
I don't know my guess would be yes I
could be totally wrong in that to
definium feel free to correct me. I am
guessing the answer is yes with MM120
but what that says to me is hey 12 weeks
of relief with GAD generalized anxiety
disorder which I've been clinically
diagnosed with that and OCD like 12
weeks is pretty good and it seems like
at least according to the data in this
study the minimum effective dose would
be 100 micrograms. Now, 100 micrograms,
at least for me and for a lot of people,
you will be tripping your balls off. Not
to get too technical. Wait a second,
dude. It says that this was done at
Neuroscape at UCSF.
>> Was it really?
>> This is Adam's lab.
>> No [__] Are you serious?
>> I'm dead serious. I just clicked through
on it. It says phase three trial of
MM120 for GAD.
>> Trial. This is our buddy.
>> This is our buddy Adam. Okay. Well, I
have a text that I need to send them.
>> Oh my god,
>> that's awesome. I wonder if I indirectly
funded this because I helped fund some
of Neuroscape stuff. That's funny. I
>> Isn't that hilarious?
>> Yeah, I did not look at that. That's
hilarious. Small world.
>> Yeah.
>> Okay, there you go. So, you know, it's
interesting for GAD. We were talking
about dementia.
There's a case report with highdosese
salosabia mushrooms. I don't think it
was actually psilocybin synthesized
looking at this particular I think it
was a Japanese elderly woman with
dementia may have been Alzheimer's who
took I can't believe they did this to
her
>> five grams right
>> yeah and then she took five grams so
Terrence McKenna heroic dose somehow
fell asleep for like 19 hours [laughter]
or something obscene which would be very
very worrisome if you're the child of
said parent wakes up and then starts
having like whole expositional
conversations
in contrast with her previous
monoselabic or or single word responses
to things and it was transient. It
didn't last forever but it raises some
very interesting questions. I've seen at
least some case reports also with LSD
producing similar effects and I've been
interested in this for probably a
decade. I've hypothesized this could be
the case. It's just like, do you really
want to give your parent like under what
circumstances is it ethical
>> to give someone hallucinating?
>> See, I could never do that to my mom
because she was always anti all this
stuff.
>> Yeah.
>> And then the second, god forbid they
have a bad trip. Like why would you want
to put them through that, you know? So,
it's curious. I was sent something by
someone I won't mention, but a very
interesting case report on micro doing
with LSD
>> with someone with dementia. But did it
work?
>> Yeah.
>> Oh, really?
>> Yeah. And in terms of similar to the
ketones, not saying the mechanism is the
same, but producing much more verbal
fluidity, right? Going from like, uh,
I'm good. It depends,
>> right? I have relatives who are limited
to that now. Like, they're basically
giving answers that are non-answers.
Sounds good, right? Like these things
that you could use as a reply to
anything, right? They're not necessarily
groing what's happening
to full paragraphs,
>> right? Which means to my interpretation,
it's like offline to online, right? It's
a really stark difference because with
the one word, two-word answers, like you
don't actually know if they're
understanding what's happening.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Do you have some MM120 on
you right now?
>> No, [laughter] I don't. I don't. If I
did, I would probably not take
>> the podcast. If you see a weird cut in
the the video and then we get infinitely
smarter. Yeah, you [laughter] you'll
know.
>> Little glitch here there. Yeah, exactly.
It's a flash and all of a sudden we're
just like, yeah, for smarter I would
keep it probably to 20 mics or below.
We'll see. But, you know, I found this
pretty interesting for for GD
especially. And then for the dementia
piece, but it raises a lot of ethical
questions.
>> What is ethical to use as a treatment
and someone who cannot give consent?
>> Right. Right.
>> That's a tough gnarly problem. Right.
>> Yeah.
>> Especially if you're dealing with stuff
that is not exactly prescription
medication.
>> Yeah. I mean, that's the whole thing. If
it goes sideways, you feel like an
[__]
>> Well, and to put it mildly.
>> Yeah. To put it mildly. But if it's
amazing and it gives you another, you
know, half day with a parent or a loved
one and you can full have conversations
and they see you and you see them in a
way that you hadn't in 6 months like or
a year. Like that's amazing, right? or
if it potentially slows the decline,
>> right? I I think it's too much to hope
for a reversal, frankly.
>> Yeah.
>> But there are some strange phenomena out
there, man. Like there's this phenomenon
called terminal lucidity where someone
like on their deathbed when they've been
off this. There's that book that I told
you read. Did you read that?
>> I'm not the afterlife book.
>> No, I didn't read that.
>> Okay. Cuz they they talk about that.
>> This is well this is well documented
where people suddenly they've been
basically vegetative,
>> right? or completely unable to respond
>> in their last two days. They come fully
lucid. Yeah,
>> they become totally lucid. They have
full-blown extensive conversations.
That's why what the [__] is going on?
>> Dude, I'm telling you, it is so weird to
me that we think like like a lot of the
things that we do in physical form, like
what we do in life mimics nature in many
ways. And all of our data is like backed
up in the cloud. And we're like, "Oh,
we're not backed up in the cloud in any
Right. And then there's these people
with like full-blown entanglements in
their brain, fullon, you know, the
Alzheimer's for like a decade and they
become completely
>> lucid. Where is that coming from?
>> Okay, I see what you're saying. I wasn't
tracking that fully for a second, but if
I'm hearing you correctly, it's like if
it's all
>> localized No, I'm saying like if all of
that ability is localized within the
confines of the skull.
>> Mhm.
>> How do you explain
>> right
>> this given all the structural
deterioration?
>> Exactly. Exactly. Yeah. I don't have
good answers for that. I just don't. It
is a well doumented, as far as I know, a
well doumented phenomenon.
>> So, it's like, go figure that one out. I
mean, I'm not qualified. Way above my
pay grade. It's
>> crazy, man.
>> It's wild.
>> It is wild.
>> So, I'll give a shout out to somebody.
We're not going to open this right now
cuz we'll start chewing on them and
we'll be up all night.
>> Is that the 120?
>> No, this is Newtonic.
Nu T O N I C. No tropics. See, that's a
pun. No tropics. cuz these are
toothpicks that I was given by a
podcaster you may recognize named Chris
Williamson. And they they have like 20
>> I want to say 20 I might be getting that
off but like 20 25 milligrams of
caffeine in each toothpick.
>> Oh wow.
>> And there are a couple of other
nutropics aka coffee. Yeah. smart trucks
in there and they're great
>> because if I have cups of coffee, I will
chug a cup of coffee and then if it gets
refilled, I'll chug another cup of
coffee and it's a problem. These
actually is in terms of pacing
>> have been fantastic. So that's been my
sort of not exactly quite as interrupt
for people who get that but sort of
[laughter]
ad libidum interruptus. Yeah, the
avoiding overconumption of coffee and
other stimulants. This helps me to kind
of pace it cuz even if I chew on this
thing until it's fragments of wood, max
I can squeeze out of it is 20 25
>> milligs.
>> What else do you got, Kevin?
>> Yeah. I mean, the only other thing that
I have that I think is is interesting is
what's happening in the world of I don't
want to talk a lot about AI because I'm
just frankly AIDed out, but I will say
that the idea that we can all now kind
of take control of
our productivity and pretty much
anything that we want to control now,
like device-wise,
>> we can do with just a few simple prompts
on AI. And I had a buddy that came over
to my house and he was like, "Hey, you
got cameras in your house." I have
something called ubiquity, which is
like, you know, like they have cameras
and there it's a very common kind of
household type situation when you want
to have security system, front door
thing, cameras, sensors, water detectors
underneath things in case things leak
and you're out of town, whatever.
>> And so I've got this whole setup and
he's like, "Hey, you know, they have a
full-on API where you can just tell
Claude or whatever to code against it."
And I was like, "Okay, this is
interesting." Well, like, well, what can
it do? And so, the cameras now have AI
sensors where they can detect who it is
that's walking in.
>> So, it's like, "Oh, Tim's coming up to
your door. Oh, that's your daughter.
That's your dog." What? It detects my
dog, Toaster. Like, it sees him and it
puts it like a little dog emblem above
his head when he's walking around and it
knows that it's Toaster. But the crazy
[__] is I was like, "Okay, well, what if
I can go further and I can tell it to do
actions because there there's a speaker
hooked up to as well." So that's for
security. Yeah.
>> So basically, if anyone loiters in my
alleyway and it detects it, it's like I
have I play some like really funky [__]
where it's like detected like loiter in
the alleyway like or whatever. And just
to scare people off in case they're
>> I am the bad man.
>> Yeah. Well, I mean, you could draw
little areas around where they shouldn't
be, which is like at your door fiddling
with your door, and say, "If they stand
here for more than 30 seconds, play said
audio out of speaker."
>> So, I was like, "Okay, this is
interesting. Well,
>> what if when I walk in my house,
>> if I'm wearing like a hat of like my
favorite sports team and they're
playing, it like reads me the scores
like I walk in." Mhm.
>> So you can think about all these things
where it's doing stuff based on your
activity, right? So like if you're out
there gardening, it'll be like, "Hey
Kevin, I noticed that the plant over
here wasn't watered enough or like so
it's watching all of this stuff."
>> And so there's a lot of if then then
that kind of situation like if I see you
doing X. So, like the latest I have is I
programmed it so when it sees the
license plate on my car,
>> it automatically knows to open the gate
>> because it knows it's me.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> And the camera looks at the license
plate on the freaking car, checks it
against the database, and allows me in.
How crazy is that?
>> And for people that are listening, I'm
not talking about $10,000 systems. The
camera is like $200.
>> Anyone can do this at home, you know?
>> It's just wild to think about. Finally,
we had all these these kind of discrete
systems that you know I had some Nest
stuff and I had some Google Home stuff.
Now they're all talking to each other.
>> So you can just do kind of really crazy
I know you would like this because
>> you're the kind of person that you've
told me before like you don't like to
answer your door cuz if the delivery
person is like Tim then all of a sudden
your address is all over the internet
>> docs. Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean, I know you said you don't
I'm also pretty AIed out, but at the
same time, it's like I can't I can't
resist going back to the opium den. It's
so fascinating.
>> What are you doing now with the with the
eye stuff?
>> Well, I mean, I'm more curious to hear
your thoughts and predictions, frankly,
because I think you're better at it. But
>> I mean, I'm using clawed code with
various APIs to do tons of like inbox
analysis and stuff, right? I'm doing a
20 year retrospective analysis of angel
investing.
>> It's like who made what introductions,
which companies did I not reply to that
ended up being successes, which did I
turn down that ended up being
>> really important.
>> You really want to do that to yourself.
>> Well, I suspected it would be worse than
it was. I actually have not I haven't
missed that many explicit opportunities.
I wanted to test my own stories against
data, right? because I have all sorts of
stories, right, about why I did certain
things, why certain things worked out,
>> and I have certain stories about my
>> batting average. And I'm like,
>> but is it true?
>> Right? Really, is it really true? Let's
look at some hard numbers. The sad
truth, and I have a buddy that wears the
bracelet, and you've seen me with the
necklace around the it categorizes your
AI and listens to you 24/7.
>> Yeah. It's about 70ish% that we think we
know, but is actually what we know.
>> Yeah.
>> Out of the 100% of like what we think we
know. This is the truth. I said I wanted
a dark chocolate bar at 7:00 p.m.
>> Yeah.
>> It's like, no, you said it at 5 and you
said it this way. You know,
>> you said it was milk chocolate.
>> Yeah, exactly. So, it's always about 20%
off from where you actually think your
brain's at.
>> Sure.
>> Which is brutal.
>> Well, plus I mean, that's like last
week, right? If you're talking about
like 15 years ago.
>> Exactly. I mean, if you listen to any
Genesis story of any startup, you're
like, [screaming]
"Wait a minute now." Like, this is like
a startup comic working on material, but
he's been working on this one 5minute
bit so long that now he believes that's
actually truth.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, the sanitizing and the editing
of these startup Genesis stories is
hilarious. And there's no reason to
think that I would be or you would be
exempt from it,
>> right? When you're telling your own
story, even if you're just telling it to
yourself. So, what's the number one
thing that you've learned by applying AI
to your life in this fashion? Like,
what's the thing where you walked away
and said,
>> "Damn, that was insightful and I'm going
to change my behavior or I learned
something new about myself that I
wouldn't have if I had not used AI."
Well, I think from a holistic health
perspective, by holistic I mean having
enough data related to medications,
supplements, predispositions, side
effects, what happened to me 2 weeks
ago. The LLMs have been incredibly
helpful. I mean, the picture that they
get and the speed with which they can
deliver an answer that I can interrogate
is just incredible. What did you learn?
Like what was the thing that you
>> I mean, honestly, it's mostly avoiding
disaster, right? It's like, are any of
these things contraindicated with one
another? Could A, B, or C explain D? And
you have to keep in mind these things
can still hallucinate, but you can I
don't want to say eliminate that, but
minimize it by just fact-checking across
LLMs. There's that. I would say that
there's a lot of insight on hopefully
that that can translate to future
decision-m related to investing, which
investing for me is not just amassing
more chips. What's fun about investing
to me is it's a way to scorecard your
thinking and decision-m.
>> It's just a very objective way to decide
if something was the right or the wrong
decision. And you can fine- slice that.
And there are ways that you could maybe
question that. But
if you're asking yourself, "Was I
thinking well last month?" That's not a
very helpful question. Where do you go
from there?
>> Mhm.
>> If you're logging maybe every decision
you make every day and then trying to
cross reference outcomes with blah blah
blah, like, "Yeah, but you're never
going to do that."
>> Mhm.
>> But when you're making relatively
frequent investments, you can do that.
You can also run counterfactuals, right?
What if I did the opposite? What if I
had not sold that? What if I had kept
that? What if I had done this? What if I
had done that? Is that worth your time,
though? At the end of the day, you could
throw everything into the S&P 500 and
just go to bed.
>> Well, there's that. I would say it's
worth it to me because I find it
interesting. I actually enjoy the
intellectual exercise of it. But
otherwise, I would say with in terms of
like how AI has has impacted me, I would
say that the honest answer is not that
much because most [__] isn't worth doing
in the first place. People are finding
very very clever ways to expedite
automating workflows of all different
types and doing something well does not
make it important or worth doing in the
first place. So there's a lot I think
the level of [__] that is being done
just at a very fast efficient rate is
skyrocketing.
>> Yeah.
>> But simultaneously there are definitely
cases where
I look back at say this analysis of 20
years of stuff to do that manually would
be impossible.
>> Sure.
>> All right. It would take me a year
full-time with multiple people to do
that.
>> And with a claude code, Gmail API and
leaving my computer running for a
handful of hours a few times, it's like
what you get back is [__] incredible.
Yeah.
>> Like it's unbelievable. And I haven't
even scratched the surface.
>> Yeah. I will say also another way that
AI has maybe affected my life in a
net negative way and I'm not we have
another mutual friend who maybe we
shouldn't name who feels very similarly
is [laughter] we'll bleep that out but
yeah Jesus Christ so if you train
AIS on your writing
they're really good
>> and I think I feel this is a stretch of
a comparison obviously cuz I'm not
an adept like a world class Go player,
but when Alph Go defeated one of the top
Korean players,
>> he was kind of like, I'm done. Like, I
don't find joy in this anymore.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> If we're playing against machines.
>> Yeah.
>> And when I see these AIs very
beautifully, I'm not going to lie, and
they're we're like in the top of the
first inning, right? This stuff is going
to get so much better. spit out stuff
that is so much better.
>> Yeah.
>> I mean, I can still write, but what they
can do in 30 seconds is what would take
me 30 hours. And I'm just like, [__] It
really drains the motivation for me to
put in those 30 hours.
>> Yeah.
>> Why wouldn't it? Of course it would.
Right.
>> Yeah. But in some sense, you can
consider it a really good co-pilot
because for it to come up with novel
ideas that would engage an audience
that's still the holy grail where it's
not quite there yet, right? Like it's
going to make you sound it's going to
button up your copy and it might expand
upon it in ways that you wouldn't, but
it's not going to come up with the
original thesis for the whole thing,
right? Yeah. It's going to have trouble
with the original thesis, but even
there, I think it does a pretty good
job. getting better. I haven't tried
with writing stuff.
>> Well, if you just do a data dump and
you're like create amazing.
>> Oh, you sent me that link.
>> Yeah. If you just do a data dump, you're
like create.
>> Remember you sent me that link. You were
like, "What should Tim do in the next 5
years?"
>> Oh, yeah. That was good.
>> That was really interesting. Tell people
what you did because they might find
this they could apply this to their own
life.
>> Sure. So, you could do this in whichever
model you're using, whether it's, you
know, Claude or Chat GPT or whatever.
>> If it knows you,
>> you can tie in your inbox, too.
>> Yeah, you can tie in your inbox. In my
case, I didn't do that. But if it has
enough history on you, you can just ask,
"What do you think I should do in the
next 5 years? What might be some
rewarding paths of exploration?" I think
I put something like that.
>> What are three to five ideas that you
think could be rewarding career
exploration in the next x period of
time? So for people listening, if
they've used AI for, let's call it 3 to
6 months, and you've probably given it
several hundred things to think about,
it will span across those conversations
as long as you turn this on. It's I
think it's on by default now, but it
used to be an opt-in thing. We're going
to say allow the AI to look cross
conversation, so it has a holistic
understanding of who you are. And the
answers were [__] outstanding.
>> Yeah. I mean, really, really good.
>> Yeah.
>> And I sent it to a few friends, sent to
you. I sent it to a few of my closest
friends and they were like, "That's
pretty [__] good."
>> Yeah. I
>> It was really cool. Some of the ideas I
was like, "Damn, you should do that,
dude." It had this one business idea for
you to do and it wasn't a book and I was
like,
>> "Dude, I texted you back. I was like,
that's awesome. Like, go build that."
>> There were business ideas. There were
certainly kind of nonrevenue
but philosophically aligned ideas. It
was shocking to me. So that's actually a
very good example of something that has
deeply informed what I'm mulling over as
I imagine the future. I was like, man,
that actually is a really good because
keeping in mind I'm asking questions
about
>> things of interest, things I like,
things I don't like. I am asking
questions about
different scientific interests related
to Sciate Foundation, my nonprofit
foundation.
>> I'm asking questions about investing.
I'm asking questions about writing. I'm
asking questions about relationships.
I'm asking questions about organizing
trips for friends. I'm asking so many
different questions.
>> Am I still on the board? You're a
nonprofit. I
>> think you're like secretary or
something.
>> Yeah, some [laughter]
heard anything about it.
>> Yeah. I don't know. Maybe you were
honorably discharged. [laughter]
>> I don't think you did. I never heard any
paperwork around it. I haven't heard
anything in like 3 years. I'm like,
okay.
>> Yeah. Well, I said it was going to be a
light lift. It's a light lift.
>> Light lift. [laughter]
>> That's a very good example, right? I
mean that that may be the best example
because if that even 10% informs like a
major next chapter
like that's a big deal for me certainly
>> and it makes me think a little bit about
podcast listeners especially readers
also but to a greater extent podcast
listeners who come up to me and most
most listeners I run into are really
great and not I mean there are always a
couple of weirdos But most are fantastic
and they'll say something often like,
"I'm so sorry you don't know me at all
and I feel like I know you." And what I
say a lot of the time is actually if you
listen to my podcasts every week or even
every month, you do know me pretty well.
>> Yeah.
>> And then you think about
>> a machine that never forgets.
>> Yeah.
>> It's going to know you pretty damn well.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Of course.
>> And it's spooky in a way.
>> Yeah. But I started getting more out of
the LLMs when I started asking
questions. Now, you have to be, I think,
a little careful with outsourcing this
and absolving yourself of responsibility
to think about these things. But when
you ask it open-ended personal questions
in the way that you would ask a close
friend, right?
>> What do you think are three to five
creative ways I might explore things
professionally in the next 5 years?
>> Yeah. as opposed to something that you
think is more suitable for a robot.
>> Yeah. Yeah.
>> You get some really interesting
responses.
>> That's so cool. That's a great use case.
>> Yeah.
>> The one thing I've been playing around
with lately that I haven't told you
about yet, but you know, I think about
all these AI startups and everyone
that's creating all these different apps
and all that stuff. And for me, you
know, that's kind of fun to watch as a
kind of bystander being like, "Oh, cool.
You're going to make this." But I I
really want to explore things that just
no one has done before. It's always been
interesting to me more than just like it
iterative kind of like sanding down the
rough edges. A lot of startups go will
go out there and be like, "Hey, you know
what sucks is word processing doesn't do
this, so I'm going to like make a
slightly better word processor. I'm just
making this up." But I like the kind of
wilder crazier like I'd rather have it
fail and say I did something new than
just do something boring. If that makes
sense. Oh, I get it.
>> And so lately, what I've done is
>> part of why I have so many fatalities.
>> So many fatalities. [laughter] Yeah,
exactly. Same. What I've done lately is
I've taken I went and bought a bunch of
these decks of cards on Amazon that are
values cards.
>> What does that mean?
>> Meaning like they give you like a deck
of a hundred things and like what are
your core values?
>> Okay. Yeah.
>> And you're like empathy or kindness or
like you like flip through them
>> and the way they typically work is that
you have like a really high value, a
medium, and a low value. And then you
put them into different stacks and then
you walk away and you say, "Oh, this is
my high value stack of things that are
my core values that mean a lot to me."
And it might be 10 or 15 different
cards, right?
>> And what's interesting is to do that
with like friends and partners and
things like that. And then compare them
and say, "Hey, what do we align on? What
we don't?" And I can imagine for like an
intimate partner, this would be a pretty
important thing to do, right?
>> And so I started there and I'm like,
"Okay, well, I'm going to scan these
cards in and then I'm going to pair it
down and make these core values where
you come in and say, "This matters to
me." Almost like a swiping like, you
know, dating app or something like,
"Yes, I'm into
>> yes, I'm into empathy." No, I'm not.
>> Yeah. Exactly. But you swipe through
them and then when you're done with
that, then you've got your list of like
these values and they can change over
time. And so I think the important thing
is to log that and say these are my
values today but tomorrow one might
shift a little bit right and then I
thought about contractual bonds and so
like the working title I have for it is
just called bond and where I can say
like with a partner I'm going to create
a contract with you where we both have
to shake on it meaning like a virtual
shake. You think of it almost like a sim
city like situation. this is my city,
this is her city or a friend's city and
we're going to agree that I take the
trash out every Tuesday night
>> and there's an emotional shake on both
sides. And if I break this bond,
it results in what? And so from the
partner's side, it will result in a 1 to
10 on how much damaging this is to me.
So not taking the trash, I'd probably be
like, "Ah, that sucks because the trash
is going to overflow." That's probably a
three to most people, right? And so then
I kind of get negative points in case I
break that bond. But what's interesting
though is that will link back to a core
value of theirs and a core value of
mine. And I [clears throat] want to show
up as a good partner and there will be a
core value associated with that. And
then you could see those bonds between
multiple people. And the reason I say
this is because I've always been one of
these people historically that have said
yes to so many things and then be a last
minute. I'm the worst at that, you know,
where I'm like I'm in and then I'm like
I'm an introvert. I'm out, you know, at
the last minute, right?
>> And so I just think that there needs to
be a system where
>> almost like a LinkedIn for like values
and trust and bonds. There's a great
Wueng quote that's like word is bond and
ultimately like I really believe that
like there's something really cool about
saying you know we have the better
business bureau that's like the best we
got, right? Like oh this person they did
well by their customers 2,000 times.
What about individuals and saying like,
"Hey, this person was always empathetic
towards me or this person was kind and
helped me move on a Sunday."
>> What prompted all this?
>> I don't know. I'm just thinking about
it.
>> Just like the thing I think about is
that there
>> such a satisfying answer.
>> No, hold on. Let me give you the real
answer.
>> I call this dark information.
>> Dark information.
>> Yeah. So, dark information is
information that exists in the real
world, but we have yet to put in
physical form.
>> Okay? And so right now you and I have a
trust thing.
>> You know that if the camera was turned
off, there are certain things that you
can tell me that you're pretty certain I
will not tell anyone else,
>> right?
>> Every once in a while I do, [laughter]
but you know where that line is, right?
>> But that hasn't been concretized in any
type of like visual real format.
>> And so there's something interesting.
I'm just brainstorming with you in real
time because we've had a couple of
drinks. But like my point is if there
was a system where I could say I've
created these bonds, I've built up this
reputation,
>> but it would also give me a way to
reflect back and be like, you know what,
I can see now historically that I've
often bailed on events that I've signed
up for. Let me improve that in myself.
Right. The whole point of what you
brought up a minute ago was
>> if I use AI to go back historically and
look across things, I can detect these
trends and then make course corrections
based on those trends. Right. Yeah.
>> And so there's something interesting
about this idea of there are these
different facets. So there's these like
emotional facets we have with every
individual. How might we track those?
Well, what jumps out at me about this is
maybe a cool use case would be
identifying. You could write it out or
you could have cards your values, but
maybe to put a finer point on it, the
type of person you believe yourself to
be.
very different than what people perceive
you to be
>> or the type of person you want to be.
And then it's like, let's take a look at
your calendar and your email and your
iMessage to see how much your story of
what you think you are or what you want
to be matches up with your behavior and
then you get a report card. I built a
prototype for exactly this. So remember
maybe seven years ago you did a 360
review for me.
>> Yeah, those things are brutal. For
people that don't know what 360 reviews
are, it's like you give 10 of your
friends to somebody, they interview
them, they collect all the data
anonymously.
>> Could also be like co-workers,
employees,
>> co-orkers, employees, friends, whatever.
And then you get a report back being
like, here are the deficiencies and
positives that this person brings.
>> Anonymized.
>> Anonymized. And they are very different
than what you think you're you how you
show up.
>> Totally.
>> And so like that's the idea.
>> I literally was looking at mine from
like 12 years ago.
Yeah, I know.
>> So tough.
>> I know cuz you get it back and you're
like, who said this?
>> I know some of it is brutal.
>> I think I know what you said, by the
way. Do you ever use the word child
rearing?
>> Child rearing. [laughter]
>> Would you ever say that?
>> Child rearing. I mean,
>> to throw me off. Would you ever say that
>> to throw you off the sun trail?
>> Because before I had kids, somebody in
my anonymous 360 review said like, "Oh,
he's going to have a hard time with
child rearing." Oh no, that wasn't me.
>> I'm like, who the [__] would say [__] I
don't have any friends that even have
that in their vocabulary. And I'm like,
the only person that could do that would
be Tim trying to throw me off with a
[__] smartass word.
>> No, that wasn't me. That wasn't me. That
[laughter] wasn't me. No. No. I think
I'd be able to identify whatever
response. That's the one thing that
stuck with me after like 15 years. I'm
like, [laughter] that man, you're lucky
if you got off of that. I've got so much
more. Good lord.
You know what I've been doing that has
been really helpful because the blank
page is something I struggle with with
writing which is part of the reason why
the AI is so demoralizing in a sense
because the LLM's within like 30 seconds
are just like boom how you like me now
try to match that
>> but using even though I certainly don't
know the future of this company because
it might get replaced by features that
are innate to X Y or Z but whisper flow
oh god I love it. Yeah. So using Whisper
Flow as a data dump,
>> I wish I was an investor.
>> You may you may have recommended this to
me. I can't recall, but
>> basically doing a dump of a conversation
as I'm walking with Whisper Flow,
>> into a note on my phone,
>> then taking that, dropping into Claude,
asking it to like clean it up and turn
it into something readable
>> has been so helpful. Not necessarily for
publication, but for emails, especially
uncomfortable emails. You're like, "God,
like I just like I'm putting it off.
procrastinates. I don't want to do it.
>> Just doing like a 10-minute brain dump.
It's shocking how quickly things come
together. Like I incredibly helpful. And
I'll just give a shout out to my friend
Alain Lee, co-founder of Exploding
Kittens. He recommended this headset cuz
I was on a call with him. I'm like,
"Man, that audio is awesome. What are
you using?"
>> Can you put it on just for the viewers?
It's going to look as good as I hope it
does.
>> It looks so good.
>> Yeah, it's pretty good, right? So, this
is the Shocks S H O KZ open meet U
openear bone conduction headset. So, he
was talking and I'm like, "What the hell
are you wearing?" I was like, "The audio
is really good." So, it looks pretty
dorky. This is like a
>> No, it's great. [laughter]
>> And the bone conduction is right here,
effectively on my cheekbones. And when
you first use them, you're like, "Wait a
second. I feel like this is playing out
of speakers. Like, this is nonsense.
This is complete BS." But then you
totally plug your ears and you can still
hear perfectly well.
>> Which is crazy. And what I like about
these is a the audio quality is great
and you know the connectivity varies,
but the audio quality is fantastic. You
can hear. So if I'm like walking my dog,
walking Molly and I want to be able to
hear traffic and so on, I can use this
cuz I especially if I'm using Whisper
Flow to data dump into a text file of
some type, I don't really need to be
listening. It's not like I'm on a phone
call or a Zoom call or something.
>> So, I find this very very helpful so
that I can actually pay attention to my
surroundings.
>> And that's all I got. It's basically
this and AirPods. I mean, there there
are other headphones that I will use for
professional recording and stuff, but
thus far, I'll share one more tech thing
real quick. These this little baggie
here is the Sennheiser Pro Audio
Condenser Microphone. It's very simple.
I've just been very impressed with the
audio when I'm on the road recording
stuff for the podcast like intros or
sponsor reads or whatever. It's just a
simple lav mic. It's so simple. But the
audio quality, even in a hotel room that
is really bouncy, lots of glass, lots of
metal where it should sound terrible.
>> If I use a fancy like this is a sure mic
that we have right here. If I were to
use this exact mic, cuz I have it at
home,
>> y
>> in some of these bouncy rooms, it would
sound worse, I'm not kidding, than what
I get for my purposes.
>> Crazy
>> with this.
>> It's pretty wild. And I love Sure. I use
their mics on a lot of podcasts. But in
terms of minimizing bounce,
>> yeah,
>> for whatever reason, this little baggie
that I can stick in a pocket, right,
it's like this is my portable
sort of recording studio.
>> Have you recorded on the iPhone with it?
I have.
>> It sounds good.
>> It sounds great.
>> That's amazing.
>> And I don't have my phone with me. There
is
>> an app that you can use for really
highfidelity recording. It's called
>> like fite or something like that.
>> It's like lossless recording, right?
>> Lossless recording. It's like f e r r i
t e something like that. I'll put the
link in the show notes
>> for this for people who are interested.
The quality is absurd. And you can also
use descript or one of these programs to
do AI cleanup. And it's crazy.
>> Yeah. You didn't even need sadly. You
don't even need to script anymore. Like
you can just use all the models do it.
Gemini is actually quite good at
multi-modal
>> audio video all that stuff.
>> Oh, cool. Gemini, honestly, I've been
using Gemini more and more just because
it's such plugandplay with fast with G
Suite also.
>> Yeah. I mean, 35 Flash like is a great
model. Although the new Sonnet just came
out and that's from Anthropic that just
came out and that's I haven't played
with it yet because it was literally
launched today and it's it's supposed to
be fantastic.
>> What do you think the landscape looks
like in a few years? You've got
Anthropic and OpenAI racing to IPO. See
where that goes. You've got Mythos Fable
taking off.
>> Mythos is out tomorrow, right?
>> Back out tomorrow, right? Okay. Was a
national security threat yesterday but
it isn't today.
>> Exactly.
>> What do you think? I mean I think the
>> It's the big three is three players.
It's Google, Anthropic, and OpenAI.
>> Mhm.
>> And X is trying and I would never ever
count out Elon obviously like he has the
funds to make it happen. Well, also
Anthropic and Google are buying excess
capacity from Colossus, right?
>> Yeah. But that means that their product
isn't working.
>> Yeah.
>> Because they bought that capacity for
themselves,
>> right?
>> So that means that no one's using Grock,
you know? I mean, I actually like Grock.
I use Grock more than people might
realize. Well, here's what's interesting
about it
>> for current events and synthesizer.
>> Yes. So, it has direct access to the X
API and that it has actually X tools
built into GRO. So, if you want to like
get like you said current events, news,
things like that. And they've also said
that it is one of the most grounded
models and doesn't hallucinate. So, that
it's really good at. And so on dig when
we relaunch it and we use a lot of AI to
kind of come up with the different
stories and all that. We use it a ton
because we want that grounded
information that is true, you know, and
so it's really important to have that.
And I I don't know. I mean, I think I
wouldn't count them out. I should
probably include them in that list.
>> So big three. What do you think things
look like in two years? You're very good
at this. I'm not saying obviously this
is just [__] bullshitting and
speculating, but
>> what's your guess?
>> I mean,
>> I'm pretty heavy into Alpha. thanks to
you which uh
>> you had in Alphabet.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. I mean
>> and then they had a 40% pop on a $4
trillion company.
>> What is going on? I mean
>> I haven't even watched. Is it up?
>> Oh well I mean look this was a while
back that I mean a while back in AI time
which is like dog years. So by that I
mean like five months ago.
>> Yeah. Exactly. Five months is like 10
years now. So here is why I like Google.
They own the full stack. So they have
their own chips. Yeah.
>> And so one of the things that I did a
deep dive on was the chips that they are
building. They really confused the
industry. It's my understanding that
they made them insanely high bandwidth
and kind of memory throughput when
everyone was like, "Hey, why are you
opening up these channels and making
them so high bandwidth for this kind of
like data flow, right?" And I talked to
Buddy and he was like, "Yeah, everyone
was confused at first when they saw the
architecture for their their latest AI
chips." And then they realized that we
live in a world right now where a model
drops like Fable goes live tomorrow on
Wednesday, right?
>> And the next OpenA model goes live, you
know, in two weeks or whatever cuz they
have that rumored one. It's like old
software deployment where it was like
model trained released out. Model
trained released out. That's the cadence
we're on right now.
>> What Google is betting, and I know I
know they're all thinking this, but what
Google's betting with this high
throughput kind of wide memory
architecture is the future is continuous
learning.
>> And so everyone is saying like we're 12
to 18 months out, maybe a little bit
longer from self-improving models.
>> I see. Yeah. So 24/7 it's not no longer
about like oh Mythos came out today. Woo
crazy. It's not about those new models
dropping. It's about just like a child
learning.
>> Tomorrow it'll be better than today for
forever.
>> And when that happens and they own the
full stack. So Google's got the chips.
Granted they're going to be constrained
by TSMC which is the the only player
that's producing. I mean there's a few
others. Samsung and Micron and a few
others, but like TSMC is like the leader
and they're producing I believe they're
producing Google's chips as well. But
they've got the chips architecture,
they've got the models, they've got the
engineers. They're freaking I mean they
lost a great one like a week ago, but
it's crazy what they're paying these
engineers. Did you see some of this?
>> It's like a billion dollars like
situation. Like it's insane what they're
paying some of these people to like
stick around.
>> Meta was doing to poach. Also,
>> Meta I just don't think they're going to
make it, man.
>> Yeah. Listen, they have great
businesses. Instagram is phenomenal.
They've got these fantastic assets, but
I just don't think they have the talent
to pull off what these other bigs are
pulling off, you know?
>> What do the big three look like in two
years, do you think?
>> Because Google has a lot of advantages
like you like you mentioned, right? I
mean, also like vast data center
expertise. They have the data centers.
They have Android.
>> Yeah.
>> Which is like 60ome percent of the
population or something like that. So
they have the install base.
>> Mhm.
>> I have a hard time believing that if you
believe that AI inference and all the
costs associated with AI eventually kind
of settles.
>> Mhm.
>> And it's affordable. And yes, it'll
probably be like a Netflix type plan
where we're all like, "Oh yeah, that's
our extra $30 a month to get all the AI
[__] whatever." if it's coming on your
device. And also, Google's powering a
lot of Apple [__] although Apple has
some unique tech.
>> It's interesting. Apple is kind of
coming up. I wouldn't write off Apple
either. Apple's another one, but they're
probably another a couple years out. I
don't know. I mean, at the end of the
day, for me, I'm old enough now to not
want to be like, "Hey, this is the
10xer."
>> Yeah. Actually, was interesting. I
called on your podcast. I don't know if
you know this, but like four years ago,
I was like, "Dude, Nvidia is going to
crush it." Blah, blah, blah. There's
some been some dumb predictions. We've
definitely made some bad ones, too. So,
I'm not going to say it's been all good,
but we've called out some stuff. In the
world of AI, I don't think it's win or
take all.
>> Yeah.
>> Unless somebody hits some kind of crazy
escape velocity that is like truly
it's like aware. What do you think? Just
I'm curious cuz you're you're so much
better at this kind of stuff than I am.
I'm like good at my dumb little corners
here and there, but you've worked at
Google, right? And you worked on their
ill- fitted social product at one point,
right? What was it called? Can't even
remember.
>> Plus, plus, right?
>> Yeah. It was horrible. I left right
away,
>> right? And very wisely segueed to Google
Ventures. I guess my point is like when
people think consumer, not enterprise.
>> When they think AI right now, they think
Chat GPT, right?
>> Yeah.
>> Chat GPT has raised a ton of [__]
money. They've got to figure out ads
almost certainly. That's not easy. That
is very, very, very hard to do. Like I'm
pretty familiar with the ads business at
Google. Very hard to do at a high level,
right? However, when
average Joe or Jane on the street thinks
AI, they think chat GPT.
>> Mhm.
>> And when I have tried to set up the
Gmail API for Claude, the process on the
Google side is such dog [__] Like the
UX is terrible. Like it is so bad.
>> Yeah.
>> And I'd [snorts] like to think myself
reasonably decent with tech stuff. Not
as not as technical as you are, but
pretty good, I would like to think.
Nonetheless, I need someone like on my
staff to walk me through step by step to
do it because it's so counterintuitive
and their errors all over the place.
>> And then you've got, you know,
Anthropic, which is, if we are to
believe the headlines on ARR, just like
crushing, right, on the enterprise side,
like the fastest scaling business of all
time on a lot of different measures.
However, right, they've gotten a number
of pretty strong [__] slaps from the
administration.
At the same time, it seems
unlikely that any of these frontier labs
are going to be left unconstrained by
the government,
>> right?
>> So, that's like a huge question.
>> H I think China will push that.
>> Okay, tell me.
>> Well, so China's been launching new
models and they just did one like a week
ago that is on par with Fable.
>> Was that Alibaba or someone else? No,
it's uh
>> doesn't matter. But
>> yeah, so but these are open source
models. So it's actually really
interesting because China is like,
"Okay, listen. We're gonna open source
this
>> and people will use our tech." They're
almost doing it the American way.
>> Yeah.
>> Like they're not closed sourcing
anything. They're like, "Okay, here's
the free model. Come use ours because
you can run it yourself if you want
locally." Mhm.
>> And that is going to be increasingly
I think that will be increasingly common
like AMD came out I don't know if you
saw what she the CEO she's brilliant she
came out with this new box that is this
like little $4,000 box or somewhere
around there and it can run like these
massive multi-billion parameter models
locally and so those charges that you
were getting
>> for you know like $1,000 a month or
$5,000 a month or whatever in AI
expenses is now just that one box that
just runs the model locally. Now
granted, it's probably eight months
behind in terms of like the model it can
run versus the frontier model who cares
>> for a lot of people who cares
>> from a business perspective and I know
that's tightly related to all sorts of
technical considerations, but
>> where do you think Google I still hate
hate saying Alphabet. Let's just say
Google the word on the street is that
they have models that are more advanced
than Fable. They have not launched them
because one the government's going to
step in and stop them
>> and two they are very expensive to run
>> y
>> and it would cost them a lot of money.
They would lose money doing so
>> and so I think in a year we're really
like 12 months we'll really know where
Google's at
>> cuz I'm telling you they're holding [__]
back.
>> Of course they are.
>> They're holding [__] back cuz they have
the bankroll to do that
>> and it's [__] Google.
>> Yeah.
>> Like you don't understand my time there.
Sergey took me, and I'm not saying this
is a flex. I'm just like, this is just
what happened. Sergey took me and Bill
Maris, who ran Google Ventures,
>> smart dude.
>> Bill's amazing, through Google X. And
this was years ago. And we got to tour.
And he was like,
>> that's the moonshot factor.
>> It's like, dude, you already work there.
And like they make you sign [__] when
you walk in. Don't [__] say anything.
>> Google X is like the Willy Wonka.
>> So I'm like seeing the Whimos before
they even talked about them freaking 10
plus years ago, you know?
thing. And so I saw the crazy balloon
projects and a couple others they
shutter that I can't even talk about.
But I'm telling you, they're sitting on
deck that's like 5 years that like don't
underestimate how many freaking PhDs
they have working on this [__]
>> Yeah.
>> You just can't imagine what's under the
hood there.
>> Sure.
>> Yeah. So for me, I'm not a fan of like
at this point when I think about
investing into the future and this is
not investment advice. When the
anthropics and the open AI and the
Google's like you name the top five,
>> it's kind of almost like what they said
back in the day when they had the
acronym they used for like Netflix,
Google, what was the uh
>> changes all the time,
>> but you know what I'm talking about.
FANG. Yeah. Like fang was a thing and
then there's another one and there's
another one. you're going to want to own
like those five, you know, and you'll
sit back and you'll be like, "Damn, if I
only just owned Google, I'd be up like
70%." But you're like, "Oh, you know
what? In combination, I'm up like 30%,
the market's doing 10." You'll be
stoked, right?
>> Yeah. You sent me a graph. We can delete
this.
>> The NASDAQ 100.
>> Yes.
>> Yeah. So, I mean, for you looking
forward, right, cuz you bust my balls
about some of the swings that I take,
which is is good. You should No, no, you
should bust my balls. I bust it because
I'm like, Tim, what are you optimizing
for, dude? Another zero. You don't need
another zero on the bank account.
>> I get it. I get it. I get it. But I'm
asking you, right? I mean, look,
>> we're all looking for the feeling of
being alive. Part of the way I feel
alive is by taking swings, right?
>> Fair.
>> Okay. My question for you is you're not
you're not just going to do S&P 500. I
find that hard to believe.
>> I dabble.
>> Okay. So, if you were
>> I'm like you. I bought Whimo stock and
you got pissed at me because I didn't
offer you any.
>> You're such a prick. [laughter]
keeps all the the shiny stuff for
himself. He's so such a greedy little
pig.
>> I didn't know you wanted it.
>> Oh, you 100% know that I want it because
[laughter]
I sent this was actually turned out
pretty well. It's part of the reason why
I I pulled the trigger on Google was
such a simple approach. I took five
names, was it? It was like Google,
Anthropic, OpenAI, Whimo,
handful of other companies.
And
there's Versel, Crusoe, a couple of
others.
>> Damn it.
>> And and I sent this list out and I sent
it to like
>> I don't know five smart people I know
who are very very good investors, have
good track records, cross asset classes,
>> and a few of them sent that to like
their technical analysts who specialize
in different fields. And I was like,
that's when you know,
>> but I was like, h maybe, maybe not. And
I was like, you have 10 chips. Where do
you put those 10 chips as a bet? That's
it. No further guidance, no caveats, no
explanation. And look, [clears throat]
I'm not saying this is the most
sophisticated investment thesis in the
world. But you know that I wanted Whimo
because it was on that list and it was
one of the winners that came back in
terms of if we are to believe the
consensus of this small.
>> To be fair, I offered you some of my own
purchase and you you turn me down.
>> I may still take you up on it.
>> Yeah. [laughter] years to wait on the 6
months for the valuation. We just wait.
Hey, remember brother get that across.
>> Saw the news. I would love to revisit
our conversation from earlier.
>> But I think for the average person
listening like the good news is that
these companies are going out soon.
>> Yeah.
>> Like meaning they're going to be
publicly traded companies. They may seem
very expensive and very pricey and you'd
be right to say that. And so did Amazon
when it went out in 2000. You know,
>> I mean what was the market cap when
Amazon IP?
>> It was like
>> it's got to be tiny.
>> No, no, no. It's not about market cap.
It's about price to earnings, right?
Yeah. Okay.
>> So, I looked at the price.
>> Now, price to earnings will depend a
lot. I mean, it's going to be very
different for Open AI and Anthropic,
right?
>> Well, what's crazy is SpaceX is like 30%
bump on price to earnings on the peak of
Amazon. So, like SpaceX is like, did you
invest in SpaceX or No.
>> Yeah, I started investing in SpaceX like
10 12 years ago.
>> Oh, so you're stoked.
>> I mean, look, yeah, I'm fine. But, you
know, I would say here also it's like if
you're like, "Oh, I missed it because
only the fancy people get to invest
beforehand." It's like, "No." I mean,
SpaceX right now, I'm looking at the
chart, launched at 160, like had this
huge bump obviously, but then dropped
down and like you could have bought it
for 156, 154, 153, and now it's climbing
back up. I mean, there's a lot going on
here. And honestly, I still find public
equity investing terrifying cuz there's
so many sharks and there's
>> short sellers and like derivatives and
all this craziness going on and like
what happens when it's listed and put
into these indexes and blah blah blah.
Like all those dynamics are way beyond
my do the day trading thing.
>> I don't do day trading.
>> No, I'm just saying like for example
SpaceX. I don't have a position in
SpaceX, but if I did, it would be to
hold for the next 10 years. Here's a
good takeaway. You're asking like what's
what's the takeaway from like my 20 year
analysis of the angel investing? It's
still incomplete. Like there's a lot
left to do.
>> Shopify.
>> Oh god. Well, that's a good example,
right? It's like this is going to sound
so dumb and yeah, duh to so many people
who are more
just better investors than I am. But
yeah, I've done pretty well. I think the
decisions I made at the time to sell
certain things were very logical given
the information and my financial status
at the time. Totally reasonable, right?
So, I don't want to judge a good poker
play based on like where I am 20 years
hence. That's not reasonable. But the
takeaway is like you got to let your
winners run as long as possible.
>> I've lost more money by selling stocks
early than I've ever probably made
buying the original stock.
>> And the other thing I would say also for
people listening who are like, "Oh my
god, if these 1 percenters are jerking
each other off any longer, I'm going to
vomit." if you adjust and some some very
famous firm did this maybe it was
Sequoia or Benchmark I can't recall but
they looked at their gains from
initial investment all the way through
follow-on rounds to IPO and then 6
months post so after lockup for let's
just keep it simple for all intents and
purposes
>> and then they looked at what you would
have gained if you bought at IPO and
just held for like 10 years
>> and you would have paid as much or more
if you would just bought as a retail
investor.
>> Yep. That is the silver lining here,
which is I for some reason get fed all a
lot of these Instagram videos.
>> You're on Instagram so much. You send so
many Instagram [__] [laughter]
>> You do.
>> But the interesting thing about it is
>> so many times as individuals and I've
fallen into this trap as well, which is
you find something that you love and you
buy said object when you should actually
buy the company.
>> Yeah. So, so let's just pretend you're
going to spend $500 on iPhone every year
since it came out, right?
>> And there was this great woman that came
in and she was like, "Okay, how do you
just for the first four years of the
iPhone coming out, rather than buy an
iPhone,
>> put it into Apple?
>> Just put it into Apple.
>> That's so cool." And it was like
hundreds of thousands of dollars.
>> And my buddy sadly like I love you
Prager. David Prager. The second the
Tesla came out, not the first one, but
the the one that was consumer friendly,
you know,
>> he went out, he's like he had made a
little money and he's like, "You know
what? I'm going to do it. I'm going to
splurge."
>> Yeah.
>> I'm going to deck it out. I'm spend 100
grand on this thing and he got the
freaking top of the line Tesla. We did
the math for him because we're bastards
and it was like $15 million or something
like that. Had he just invested in Tesla
the second he loved the product. But the
moral of the story is if you love
something and this is going to happen
over and over again for decades to come.
If you're like, "Hey, Claude is my [__]
I use it every single day. I think it's
great because of X Y and Z." And they go
public. Like set it and forget it.
>> Come in whatever you can afford. I don't
care if it's $100 or $1,000 or $100,000.
>> It's meaningful at the end of the day.
>> That's my It's great advice. I mean,
look,
>> that's part of the reason. And I have
gotten so much [__] from this by some
VCs, I won't mention their names, who
are just like what? Because they've got
their like 30 slide our proprietary
investment thesis [__] that they show
pension funds and stuff, right? And I'm
like,
>> I just try to invest in stuff that I
will use every day. Yeah.
>> Right. And it's not true for everything
like Commonwealth Fusion Systems. All
right, I'm not using them every day, but
SpaceX, you know, I mean, outside of
Starlink, but it's like there are
exceptions, but it's like with something
like this, right, where it's like I am
>> eating close to half of my protein
calories every day of this stuff. And
I'm like, I should just invest in the
company, right? It's just like
>> that is what makes sense. You know, the
first stock I ever bought is when I was
like,
>> Delonics, [laughter]
>> that'd be something you use every day.
>> Tell it. Yeah. Can't go wrong. For
people that don't know what Dill Donics
say this Jesus. Yeah, that'll be another
round show notes. Um, but the uh it was
Pixar. Oh [__]
>> Yeah. My dad bought me some book on
stock investing. Honestly, I couldn't
make any sense of it cuz it was getting
into like price to earning and this and
that earning per share and I was like,
"Ah, I don't really understand this."
That's so cool your dad bought you that
book.
>> It was cool. It was cool.
>> Do do you like
>> That's cool.
>> It's cool.
>> It's cool. it was his his way of like
showing love, you know, like we can't
all do it the way necessarily people
want to receive it. But
>> yeah,
>> in any case, the point of that was I
loved comics. I tracked comics and
animation and I saw Toy Story number
one. I even saw shorts and I was like
that is the future. I know that's the
future.
>> Exactly. And when I was whatever 15 or
something, first stock Pixar, I have I
have the original like shareholder
poster they mailed out like last year
and jobs and stuff.
>> Oh, dude, that's amazing.
>> Yeah. And for me, it's like look at your
credit card statement.
>> Do you know what I mean? I mean, this is
not investment advice. I'm just saying
this is the way I personally approach
it. So,formational
purposes only. But it's like, yeah, if
you're spending hundreds of dollars on
like
Amazon and Amazon Prime, it's like,
well,
>> maybe, who knows?
>> Totally.
>> You know, are you going to be spending
more or less on that in 5 years? Like,
just forget about the market. Forget
about analysts like you personally.
>> Will you be spending more or less on
this in three or five years time?
>> That's exactly right.
>> Okay. And we'll put something in the
intro on this is not investment advice,
but it's like you don't need to be a
quant hedge fund manager. Well, and to
be fair, like when you look at Buffett's
portfolio and the things that he's
bought over the years, like it's the
consumer staples and the things that
were just like he's like, "Yes, more
people will want and drink Coca-Cola in
the future. It's a fantastic brand. The
margins are impeccable. It's a well-run
business. I know the CEO. It's like
prone to disruption."
>> Yeah. Exactly. In downturns, guess what?
People still drink Coke.
>> Yeah.
>> You know, it's like
>> He's also a clever bastard, though. He's
been very good with his ash grandpa
branding. He's very good at that. But
that dude is a stone cold killer
>> in terms of
>> Geico is cash machine. And
>> yeah, I know
>> being like the lender of first resort
when going sideways. People call uncle
uncle Uncle Buffett and he's like sure
here's my offer.
>> Take or leave.
>> But yes, very bright guy.
>> All right.
>> What have we missed? Uh I the only thing
I would say is that um
>> tell Doddonics.
>> Yes, that I relaunched. If you want to
learn about the latest tech and AI news,
I relaunched DIG.
>> You're showing me some numbers. That's
crazy.
>> It's crazy. We went from 20,000 people a
week using it. Now we've close to
500,000.
So it's been growing quite a bit and
it's pulling across the entire zeitgeist
of the web. So we're we're like we don't
want to start another social network.
So, we pull from X and we pull from a
few other feeds when we'll be putting in
like videos from YouTube and Tik Tok and
others and it's just been a fun little
hobby. It's a fun hobby and it's like
doing millions of page views a month and
I'm proud of that. It's like it's
awesome to see it working again. So,
it's good.
>> Digg.com
>> digg.com Kevin Rose on Instagram and
yeah,
>> sweet. What should I say? I guess
tim.blog you can find thousand plus blog
posts. If you want to read about my
cadaavver on the table, my book sales as
a result of AI, that is a crazy blog
post. I don't even know if you were
aware of this. Oh yeah, my uh
>> all format book sales.
>> Oh, I saw that.
>> Yeah. Isn't it crazy down?
>> Well, you look at the graph and it's
like stable annuity, stable annuity,
stable annuity, very predictable. And
then in 2013, because what happened in
November 2022, chat GBT 3.5, and you see
a slip by 5%, then you see a slip by
like I'm making up these numbers, but
they're close. Negative - 28%, then it's
like -49%.
>> But it turns out you're going to be
okay.
>> I'll be fine. The implications are
pretty interesting. And now if we
continue the pace in 2026 down like 67%.
These are
>> [__]
>> These are sort of compounding in the
wrong direction, right? I mean, it's not
quite the right terminology to use, but
you get it.
>> Yeah. So, stuff to think about. People
can check that out if you search AI
non-fiction Tim Ferrris. That's a blog
post. It's actually pretty interesting
read. But on a less dystopian view,
ultimately the message isn't dystopian.
Tim.blog,
Tim Ferris on Instagram, TF TF RS on
Twitter. But like honestly, I'm not so
active on the socials cuz I've deleted
those from my phone for a couple years.
You're listening to the podcast so I
don't have to sell the podcast. Oh, five
bullet Friday.
>> My diary.
>> Can you add one?
>> Can I add one? What?
>> I don't know. It's like like six
bullets.
>> Well, every once in a while if I'm lazy,
there are
>> no if I'm lazy and I'm like I don't want
to do it cuz I still I still do this
thing myself. Hold on one sec. We're
almost done.
>> Relax. You and your prostate.
>> I No, no, it's not [laughter] the
prostate. It's the fact that we had You
gave me tequila.
>> Oh, I gave you tequila. You were over
served. Hold on a second. Just give me
two [__] seconds, you old man. Old
bastard. So I know I'm going to make
this really long. [laughter] Come on. So
yeah, five bill Friday every once in a
while. You did this yourself. Turns into
six bullets Saturday if I'm just not
feeling it. But yeah, 2 million
subscribers. It's free. Easy to
unsubscribe. tim.blog Friday. And that's
all I got.
>> All right. You want to go pee, man?
>> Yeah, I will. All right. Good to see
you, buddy. Good to see you. [laughter]
Love you, brother. Love you, too.